#### Contact

bbirhiray@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/brendabirhiray-0b6b56b (LinkedIn) www.napw.com/profile/11026683/ Brenda-Birhiray/ (Other)

## Top Skills

Nursing
Acute Care
Critical Care

### Certifications

Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS)

Basic Life Support (BLS)

# Brenda Birhiray

RN-MSN, ACNPC-AG, CCRN

Orange County, California Area

## Summary

An Advanced Practice Registered Nurse with more than 12 years of experience in acute care settings. Dedicated to the profession of nursing with demonstrated leadership and team skills. Creative and adaptable to today's changing environment.

# Experience

St Joseph Hospital Travel Nurse October 2019 - Present (9 months) Aliso Viejo, California

Medical Intensive Care Unit

Memorial Hermann Healthcare System Registered Nurse February 2011 - October 2019 (8 years 9 months)

Created and implemented care plans for MICU and SICU patients with disease states such as DKA, acute MI, GI bleed, multi-organ system failure, and septic shock. Titrated hemodynamic drugs and ensured hemodynamic stability with advanced monitoring techniques and pressor support, CRRT management, balloon pumps, and hypothermia therapy. Served as Charge Nurse on regular basis. Duties consisted of managing patient flow in and out of the unit, and providing clinical oversight for staff members. Conducted central lines and Foley placement audits to prevent CAUTIs and CLABSIs. Served as Clinical Coach to new hires and graduate nurses. Served as Rapid Response Team to prevent clinical deterioration of patients outside the ICU. Collaborated with other interdisciplinary team members. Awarded the Silver CHAMPS FY2013 for honorable mention by multiple patients and peers for excellent nursing care and teamwork.

Pulse Emergency Medical Services Administrator February 2012 - January 2014 (2 years) Houston / Katy Founded Pulse EMS in 2012- A non-emergency ambulance transportation business. Served as the Administrator in all matters of operations and personnel related to the company. Coordinated all routines and inter-facility transfers within the greater Houston area and its vicinities. Developed key relationships with physician offices, patients, nursing homes and other health care entities to increase referrals to practice. Handled customer complaints in both clinical and personnel areas, and worked to facilitate a satisfactory resolution.

CHRISTUS Health

Registered Nurse

July 2007 - April 2011 (3 years 10 months)

Staff Nurse/ Relief Charge Nurse for CardiacCare Unit and Telemetry Unit, and Staff Nurse for Medical Surgical Unit

## Education

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center

Master of Science in Nursing, Adult Gerontology Acute Nurse

Practitioner · (2015 - 2017)

Texas Tech University Health Sciences Center Bachelor of Science, Nursing · (2007 - 2008)

Houston Community College Associate Degree, Nursing (2005 - 2007)